Tyson W. McCrary

3424 Cogswell Street Chattanooga, TN 37406 Cell (423) 902-9086

tysonwmccrary@gmail.com.

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Over 5 years in water system experience with regard to the Nuclear power industry. Enthusiastic engineer capable of handling cost, budget and schedule while maintaining a quality deliverable that exceed client expectations. Knowledgeable in Environmental Protection Agency laws and regulations. Efficient in engineering design and favorable in communication, computer programming, and Microsoft Office.

EXPERIENCE

2014- Present

CITY OF CHATTANOOGA YOUTH FAMILY AND DEVELOPMENT

Enrichment Tutor. - Assist young children and young adults in an after-school program. Provide assistants with homework assignments and prepare highs-school students for SAT/ACT testing.

HAMILTON COUNTY DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION

Educational Assistant/Substitute Teacher - Assist students in the Hamilton County School System.

2008-2013

SARGENT & LUNDY LLC

Assist in several plant modifications and upgrade projects in TVA Nuclear Power systems.

Bellefonte Nuclear Power Plant

Phase 1 - Reconstruct control configuration drawings for reconstruction and restart

Phase 2 - Adjust ECM&D (Engineering Construction Monitoring and Document) to reflect the current status of Bellefonte Nuclear Power Plant.

Configuration Control Assessment - Selected various plant components and compare with in-plant configuration documents/records against the information agreement between ECM&D and Test Cards.

Hydraulic Calculation for Component Cooling Water System – Using computer programming to illustrate the as-designed system to aid in determining the flow margins for the Component Cooling System which facilitates the design of the system.

Reconstruct/Re-design of the Chemical Cleaning Systems – Determine if system meets environmental standards for peroperational use at the Bellefonte Nuclear Site.

Task Manager of Preparing 10% Engineering System Design Packages for Balance of Plant (BOP) Systems for BLN approval. Packages consist of background information about system, the current configuration of system, and retrieval of documents associated with system to determine if any revisions are needed. Documents consist of system drawings, system calculations, vendor manuals and design basis information. Any open items that were not approved would be investigated for current status and placed in a database for tracking process. The main balance of plant systems consist of Main Steam, Steam Extraction, Condenser, Condensate, Main Feedwater, Heat Rejection and Condenser Cleaning.

Watts Bar Nuclear Power Plant

Revision of the Net Heat Input (NHI) of Watts Bar Nuclear (WBN) Reactor Power Re-gear of Motor Operated Valves (MOVs) in the Reactor Coolant System and Safety Injection System

Browns Ferry Nuclear Power Plant

Valve Replacement and Isolation Valves for Residual Heat Removal Service Water (RHRSW) System

2006-2007

MUELLER COMPANY

Position: 3rd Shift Supervisor 1401 Mueller Avenue Chattanooga, TN 37406

Lab Technician Office 423-698-8811

Responsibilities: Evaluate and examine chemistry of molten gray and ductile iron. Add alloys to iron for correct iron production. Perform tensile test for strength of produced iron.

2003-2004

U.S. PIPE AND FOUNDRY

Position: Metallurgical Engineer/ 2701 Chestnut Street Chattanooga, TN 37408

Sand Lab Assistant Office: Out of Business

Responsibilities: Record chemistry of iron samples; dissect samples for visualization of chemistry. Provide strength and yield test of iron samples for production. Perform test on mold and core sands for durability and strength.

EDUCATION

Tuskegee University - Graduation: July 2005 - Bachelor of Science in Engineering - Major: Mechanical Engineering